<idea-plugin require-restart="true">
  <id>com.j-light.resharper-mcp</id>
  <name>MCP Server for Code Intelligence</name>
  <version>0.2.1</version>
  <vendor email="j.light.developer@gmail.com" url="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/vendor/j-light">Joshua Light</vendor>
  <idea-version since-build="253" />
  <depends>com.intellij.modules.rider</depends>
  <description><![CDATA[
    <p>An MCP (Model Context Protocol) server that runs inside the ReSharper/Rider backend process,
    exposing code intelligence features to AI assistants via HTTP.</p>

    <p>Available tools:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><b>find_usages</b> — Find all references to a symbol</li>
      <li><b>get_symbol_info</b> — Get detailed symbol info: kind, type, params, docs, base types</li>
      <li><b>find_implementations</b> — Find implementations of interfaces/abstract classes</li>
      <li><b>get_file_errors</b> — Get compile errors and unresolved references</li>
      <li><b>search_symbol</b> — Search symbols by name across the solution</li>
      <li><b>go_to_definition</b> — Navigate to a symbol's declaration with source text</li>
      <li><b>get_solution_structure</b> — List projects, target frameworks, and references</li>
      <li><b>browse_namespace</b> — Browse namespace hierarchy</li>
      <li><b>list_symbols_in_file</b> — List all declarations in a file</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Supports C#, F#, VB, and any language with a ReSharper PSI implementation.</p>

    <p>The MCP server starts automatically on <code>http://127.0.0.1:23741/</code> when you open a solution.
    Set the <code>RESHARPER_MCP_PORT</code> environment variable to use a different port.</p>
  ]]></description>
  <change-notes><![CDATA[
    <p><b>0.2.1</b></p>
    <ul>
      <li>Performance: search_symbol and symbol-by-name resolution now use R#'s symbol cache instead of brute-force PSI tree walking — orders of magnitude faster on large solutions</li>
      <li>Fix cascading timeout bug: timed-out requests no longer block the R# thread, preventing snowball failures when parallel tool calls queue up</li>
      <li>Increase tool execution timeout from 30s to 120s to handle queued parallel requests</li>
      <li>Fix macOS plugin install path (plugins/ subdirectory)</li>
    </ul>
    <p><b>0.2.0</b></p>
    <ul>
      <li>find_usages: results grouped by project and file with counts; excludeDeclarationFile option; per-line deduplication</li>
      <li>find_implementations: direct vs indirect classification with via chain</li>
      <li>get_symbol_info: filter compiler-generated record members (operators, accessors, parameterless ctors)</li>
      <li>search_symbol: dot-qualified queries (e.g. "IProfile.Fake") match by ContainingType.MemberName</li>
      <li>list_symbols_in_file: filter get_/set_/add_/remove_ accessor methods</li>
      <li>browse_namespace: flag generated source files</li>
    </ul>
    <p><b>0.1.0</b></p>
    <ul>
      <li>Initial release with 9 MCP tools</li>
      <li>Language-agnostic PSI support (C#, F#, VB)</li>
      <li>Symbol resolution by name or file position</li>
      <li>Ambiguity detection with candidate list</li>
    </ul>
  ]]></change-notes>
</idea-plugin>
